MOHD HAFEZ BIN ABDULLAH

MECHATRONIC ENGINEERING GRADUATE

+60124113080 - m.hafez.abdullah@gmail.com - my.linkedin.com/in/hafezabdullah



Hands-on experience in mechatronic projects involving control system and mechanical aspects of the engineering field. Superior knowledge in computer system, design and analytical projects. A mature graduate achieving high leadership honors while maintaining part-time employment and a dedicated volunteer member.

EXPERIENCE

BUSINESS CONSULTANT: SME-IIUM Internship Consultancy Program

(Selangor), Feb 2014 – August 2014

- Initiated statistical analysis project that resulted in sound recommendations adopted by entire team.
- Designed space plans to account for ongoing company growth
- Assessed and re-design facility plans based on sale requirements and revised business model.

HALL MANAGER: Defense Service Asia (DSA 2014)

(Kuala Lumpur), April 2014

- Handled program complained, maintaining a positive experience for all exhibitors and visitor.
- Acted as communications liaisons between exhibitors and VVIP delegations.
- Established and maintained cooperative relationships of exhibitors and visitors interest groups.

TRAINEE ENGINEER: Jurutera Perunding Valdun Sdn. Bhd

(Selangor), Jun 2013 – Sept 2013

- Assisted senior engineer with the design of HVAC parts and system components.
- Performed heat load estimating and HVAC system sizing using Hourly Analysis Program (HAP).
- Calculated hot water demand and storage sizing, determined type of hot water system, such as electrical, solar or hybrid water heater system (VRF), which functions most efficiently and economically.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (HONS) MECHATRONIC

International Islamic University Malaysia (Selangor), January 2015

FOUNDATION OF ENGINEERING

Centre for Foundation Studies IIUM (Selangor), 2010

PURE SCIENCE

Sultan Abdul Hamid College

PROJECTS

SELF DIAGNOSTIC SYSTEM FOR AUTONOMOUS ROBOT

- Developed an efficient mechanical and electrical circuit design process.
- Completed Temperature/Direction/Velocity algorithm for self-diagnostic system using Arduino software.
- Determined most effective sensors and subsystems for error detection to be implemented on autonomous robot.

SKILLS

SOFTWARE: Visual Basic, C++, Arduino, MATLAB, AutoCAD, Carrier Hourly

Analysis Program (e-20), Microsoft Office, SCADA, CNC G-code.

TECHNICAL: Welding, Foundry, Mills, PLC

LANGUAGE: English, Bahasa Malaysia

LEADERSHIP

PRESIDENT

ACHIEVEMENT

Sekretariat Rukun Negara IIUM, 2012 -2013

- Founded SRN club in International Islamic University Malaysia
- Collaborated with various university clubs for launching a big scale project 1-Malaysia "Jejak Anak Bangsa".
- Strengthen the club with numerous program and seminars.

MEMBER OF YOUTH PARLIAMENT

Malaysian Youth Parliament, 2012

- A platform made by the government for the Malaysian youth representing each of their parliamentary constituent
- Channeled ideas, criticisms as well as discussion of youth policies made by the government for the benefit of various groups
- Simultaneously involved in the platform's policy construction. The initiative impacts the nation's youth development.

UNIVERSITY AMBASSADOR

Official Launching of Rural Transformation Program, 2012

- Launched our university student's ambassador program in RTC Perak
- The program was about educating rural citizens about financial knowledge
- Joint-venture with "Perpustakaan Bergerak" to bring books and computers to encourage their children to read